Last Updated: 2018/12/13

Benjamin Salasek

Chicago, IL | BenjaminSalasek@iCloud.com | 773.682.6443 | benjamin.website/com | GitHub: BenjaminC137

My hunger for knowledge, passion for coding and positive attitude. I'm extremely motivated and pick things up quickly.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Experience developing full stack, responsive web applications using Angular 6, TypeScript .NET, C#, MVC, SQL, HTML/CSS, and JavaScript. Collaborates in an agile environment. Strong front-end and UI design skills. Five years experience writing Arduino (C/C+ + based) software and developing electronic prototypes. Extensive researching and online courses.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages	Technologies/Frameworks	Databases	Tools/Methodologies
Arduino	.NET Core	Entity Framework	Arduino Desktop/Cloud IDE
C#	ADO.NET	MySQL Server	Brackets
CSS3	Angular 6	MySQL Workbench	Git-Hub
HTML5	ASP.NET MVC	Visual Studio	Google Chrome
JavaScript	Bootstrap		MySQL Workbench
MySQL	Entity Framework		Adobe Photoshop
SQL	jQuery		Safari
TypeScript	REST API		Visual Studio 2017
	DEVELOPMI	ENT PROIECTS	

Benjamin.Website | benjamin.website/com

- Created using Angular 6, TypeScript, JavaScript, Bootstrap, HTML5 and CSS3 and hosted on GitHub Pages
- This is my Professional Website which includes my developer portfolio
- Showcases my Arduino Projects

Interdimensional Things | interdimensionalthings.azurewebsites.net

- Built an ASP.NET MVC E-commerce website for my final project
- C#, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS3, Rest APIs, MySql and Entity Framework
- APIs: Braintree, SendGrid, SmartyStreets
- Database and website hosted on Azure

Automatic Dog Feeder (Neechi Feeder) https://benjamin.website/neechifeeder

- Designed, built and coded a physical machine that automatically feeds my dog twice daily
- Used Arduino language (based on C/C++) in the Arduino Cloud IDE
- Agitation stepper motor with twisted metal agitator, servo motor with sliding plastic plate that opens to release food, lcd to display last time fed, current time, times fed today, manual feed button, RTC module for keeping real time

Happy Weather | urldotcom.com/weather

- Simple mobile weather app using Yahoo's weather API
- Written in HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript and hosted on GitHub Pages

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Student | Coding Temple | Chicago, IL | May - August 2018

Developed projects including single page and full stack web applications using ASP.NET MVC, C#, SQL, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript and Angular 2+. These applications include self-designed relational databases, user/admin role management, and salted hashing password encryption for site security.

- Built an e-commerce website from the front-end to the back-end
- Designed the project wireframe and layout
- UI design and development using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Angular 6, Bootstrap and jQuery
- Designed the database, created tables with records and created stored procedures for external database manipulation
- Utilized bootstrap to create clean and stylized responsive web pages for all devices and browsers
- Created a Web API to allow the website to access information stored in the database
- Used CORS to allow cross domain access between API and MVC application

- Implemented LINQ queries to give access to my SQL database for CRUD functionality
- Utilized browser development tools to track layout issues and debug JavaScript content

Environment: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Angular 6.0, SQL, ASP.NET MVC, C#, .NET, Entity Framework, API

Support Specialist | Verint Systems, Inc. | Chicago | Feb 2017-June 2018

Provided end user support for staff and customer support for our website feedback product

- System management: Microsoft's AD, Exchange, Office 365, SFB, Teams, VPN, VOIP, print server, Remote Desktop
- Customer support: modified comment cards in customers' websites
- Customized via HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and JavaScript

IT Lead | OpinionLab, Inc. | Chicago | July 2015-February 2017

- 130 end users: On/Off-boarding, Windows, Mac, remote, local, Computer imaging, VOIP, Citrix VDI,
- System Engineer: Atlasssian's JIRA & Confluence, macOS imaging server, Air-Watch, SalesForce, File-share server
- System Management & Administration: Active Directory, antivirus, Cyberduck, data center & Facility access, Domain
 controller, equipment, Extranet ssh, Google Business, HipChat, LastPass, MS Exchange, MultiFactor auth, print server,
 RemoteDesktop, shipping, TeamViewer, VirtualBox, Vendor & purchasing, VOIP, VPN, Office365 migration, workstation
 & domain migrations, VOIP migration, SOC 2 compliance, user auditing, Wiki creation & Documentation

Genius (Mac Technician) | Apple Inc. | Chicago | 2007-2015

Apple Certified Mac Technician (ACMT): Mac & iOS, hardware & software support.

EDUCATION

Columbia College Chicago: Bachelor of Arts. Video. Dean's List Award

Other Skills: Adobe Photoshop, Google Docs, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Word, Microsoft PowerPoint, Atlasssian's JIRA, Scrum, Agile,

Special Skills: Graphic Design, Woodworking, Office Foosball Champion!